Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives photograph collection, 1850-1995
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series II: New Mexico.
  - Laguna, New Mexico. (Box 5)
    Two photos of the interior of a store; three photos of exterior of buildings.
  - Lamy, Archbishop John B.: Archbishop John B. Lamy of Santa Fe. (Box 5)
  - Las Vegas, NM. (Box 5)
  - Lehman, Mr. and Mrs. Carl: Mr. and Mrs. Lehman in Lordsburg, NM. (Box 5)
  - Leitensdorfer family: Photograph of a business document written in Spanish that is probably about Eugene Leitensdorfer who was a Santa Fe trader. (Box 5)
  - Lesinsky, Charles: Advertisement in the Silver City Enterprise (September 12, 1884). (Box 5)
  - Lewinson family. (Box 5)
    Mrs. Leo Lewinson (1988).
    Mr. and Mrs. Leo Lewinson in front of home in Albuquerque, NM (1988).
    Seymour Lewinson(?).
    Football team - University of New Mexico.
    Edith Sterns; Etta Vaughn; Roy Stamm; Seymour Lewinson; Nellie Booth (ca. 1890).
    L. Lesser and S. Lewinson's clothing and dry goods store (ca. 1900).
  - Lindauer family. (Box 5)
    Sam and Lillian Lindauer as children (1892).
    Sigmund Lindauer (1893; by Brund Portraits of Chicago).
    Sam, Lillian, Herman Lindauer.
    An older Sigmund Lindauer.
    Herman, Sigmund, and Albert Lindauer.
    Herman Lindauer.
    Postcard of Sam Lindauer (1910).
    Lindauer Store (Georgetown).
  - Mandel, Joseph: Joseph Mandel (1988). (Box 5)
  - Map of New Mexico: NEGATIVE of a map of New Mexico. (Box 5)
  - Map of New Mexico settlements, 1694-1850: Map of New Mexico settlements from 1694-1850. (Box 5)
  - Rosenwald, Emanuel: Emanuel Rosenwald; NEGATIVE. (Box 5)
  - Santa Fe, NM. (Box 5)
  - Santa Fe, New Mexico buildings. (Box 5)
    Interior of a new synagogue in Santa Fe (1988).
    Entrance to the Sunday school at the Old Temple in Santa Fe (1988).
    Torahs located in the New Temple in Santa Fe (purported to be the original Torahs from the first synagogue in Las Vegas; 1988).
    Church with Hebrew letters (the Tetrgrammaton) above the doorway.
    "The Guarantee."
    Square in Santa Fe (1988).
  - Seligman family. (Box 5)
    Julius Seligman; his wife Blanche Black Seligman; his son Thornton (Domingo, NM; ca. 1910); family is sitting on a cart drawn by two horses.
    Inaugural reception (1931).
    Bernard Seligman.
    Blanche Block Seligman (Mrs. Julius).
    Bernard Seligman; Zadoc Staab; Lehman Spiegelberg; Kiowa Indians.
    Sigfried Seligman.
    Julius Seligman.
    Bernalillo Mercantile Co.- building before restoration (1960s).
    Rufina Zamura (dry goods department employee for 50 years).
    Julius and Blanche B. Seligman.
    Mr. and Mrs. Siegfried Seligman.
    Seligman-Clever store (Santa Fe; probably Plaza and San Francisco St.; 1850s).
    Block print of stagecoach entering plaza from Shelby Street; Exchange Hotel; Seligman store; clock (1883).
    Four boys: Julius; Siegfried; Carl; Ernest.
    Milton Seligman (1988).
  - Shor, Rabbi David D. (Daniel): Rabbi David D. (Daniel) Shor (1988). (Box 5)
  - Spiegelberg buildings. (Box 5)
    Home with one woman and two young girls standing in front.
    Second National Bank of New Mexico.
    SpiegelberShorg Bros. General Merchandise Groceries and Provisions.
    Willi Spiegelberg house (Santa Fe; 1988).
    Plaque - Willi Spiegelberg’s house (Santa Fe; 1988).
  - Spiegelberg family. (Box 5)
    Sons of Levi Spiegelberg (ca. 1895-1900).
    "Grandpa Willi Spiegelberg and the Goldenhaired Child" (by painter Marliyn Cohen?; 1991).
    Document: appointment of Willi Spiegelberg as probate judge (1894; Santa Fe).
    Levi Spiegelberg’s sons.
    Spiegelberg brothers (ca. 1890).
    Willi Spiegelberg at age 84.
    Levi Spiegelberg (ca. 1855-60; from a reverse oil painting under a photograph on glass).
    Levi Spiegelberg (ca.1900).
    Betty Spiegelberg (ca. 1900).
    Solomon Jacob Spiegelberg (reproduction painting by Constans Mayer; 1856).
    Solomon Spiegelberg.
    Unidentified men.
  - Staab, Abraham (1839-1913): Abraham Stabb. (Box 5)
  - Synagogue cornerstone laying (Albuquerque). (Box 5)
  - Taichert, Milton. (Box 5)
    Janet Loeb interviewing Milton Taichert (Las Vegas, NM; 1988).
    Milton Taichert in front of home (Las Vegas, NM; 1988).
  - Temple Albert (Albuquerque). (Box 6)
    The original Temple Albert.
    Sam Danoff and son in California.
    Records of B'nai B'rith cemetery; photos of original documents.
    Records of Temple Albert cemetery; photos of original documents.
    B'nai B'rith cemetery; photo of original documentation.
    Temple Albert.
    Staab House Restaurant and Bar.
    Temple Albert (1899-1900).
    Document from Strong Brothers - undertakers.
    Menorah from Temple Albert.
  - Temple Beth El (Las Cruces). (Box 6)
    "Cradle Roll" - a special program for children up to the age of four; standing man is temple president Rand Greenfield; holding scroll: Leora Zeitlin; the man with the phony beard is her husband Stuart Kelter; Elaine Cohen has her back to th e camera.
    Annual Gala Dinner.
    Gala Dinner; shows Judy Karshner.
    Gala Dinner; shows the tables decorated.
    Party; Florence and Jack Levine are at the front of the picture.
    Waldman Library located inside Temple Beth El; librarian is Elsa Altshool.
    Religious school picnic (Apodaca Park).
    Classes in Talmud; Cy Stanof(?) - middle on the far side of the table.
    Temple board meeting; Joan Glickler, secretary; Paul Feil (wearing pink), treasurer.
    Temple board meeting; Rand Greenfield; Joan Glickler; Gabriel Lampert; Jack Levine.
    Torah study in the front of the Temple; Cy Stanof; Irv Rothman.
    Class entitled "(Re)Discovering Judaism."
    Rummage sale.
    Religious school choir; led by Hillel Katzir - playing the guitar.
  - Weinstock, Carol (photographer): NEGATIVES and contact sheets from the work of photographer Carol Weinstock. (Box 6)
  - Weisl family: Group portrait (1880-1885): Simon Rosa; Bernard Hood; Soul Weisl; Frances Weisl; Anna Weisl; Bertha Lesinsky; Maikias Richt; Emma Richt; Sigmund Reisl; Charles Lesinsky. (Box 6)
  - Wormser, Gustav. (Box 6)
    Gustavo Wormser's home (Deming, NM; before 1900).
    G. Wormser and Co. Store (Deming, NM).
- Series III: Texas.
  - Amstater family. (Box 6)
    John Amstater (El Paso).
    Father and mother of Molly Amstater.
    Molly Amstater's brother and his wife, Ethel.
  - Berg/Given families. (Box 6)
    Group photo (l-r): Deborah Given; Charles Given; Jennie Berg; Sol Berg; Julius Berg; horseback riding in resort town of Cloudcroft, New Mexico.
    Group photo, probably the Berg family.
  - Blumenthal store (El Paso, TX): Blumenthal Clothier store(117 South El Paso St.; 1890-1900). (Box 6)
  - B'nai B'rith (El Paso, TX): B'nai B'rith group photograph(B'nai Zion Ball Room; 1978). (Box 6)
  - Cohen, David: David Cohen's home (W. Yandell). (Box 6)
  - Congregation B'nai Israel (Galverston, TX): Laying of the cornerstone. (Box 6)
  - Congregation B'nai Zion (El Paso, TX). (Box 6)
    First home of Congregation B'nai Zion.
    View of B'nai Zion.
    Letters from Bernard Schuster about a group from B'nai Zion (1916).
    Texas Historical Commission - official historical medallion (1984).
    Interior of temple after fire (1984).
    Exterior of temple.
    Contact sheet showing exterior of B'nai Zion.
    Negative sheet showing exterior of B'nai Zion.
  - Earle, Jack: Interview with Jack Earle - circus "giant"(by Times Union; July 17, 1944). (Box 6)
  - El Paso, TX - 2f. (Box 6)
  - El Paso, Texas (cemeteries). (Box 6)
    Contact sheets: headstones from an unknown El Paso cemetery.
    NEGATIVES sheet showing headstones from an unknown El Paso cemetery.
  - Fierman, Rabbi Floyd S. (Box 6)
    Portrait of Rabbi Floyd S. Fierman (El Paso).
    NEGATIVES sheet.
  - Forchheimer family. (Box 6)
    Forchheimer store (Alpine, TX; 1921): Louis Forchheimer; dog; Louis Frank Deanda.
    Group photo: family; Pau; Mathilda; Juliette; Louis; Floreme (ca. 1929).
    Mathilda and Louis Forchheimer (ca.1939); letter from Paul Forchheimer.
  - Fox, Eugene: Eugene Fox in army uniform (1983). (Box 6)
  - Friedman, Diane. (Box 6)
    Rachel Lipson; Vicki Rosen; Diane Friedman; (El Paso; 1984).
    Diane Friedman; Evelyn Jaffe; Al Jaffe.
  - Given family. (Box 6)
    Group photo: Ken Given family (El Paso; 1982).
    Group photo: family; Thomas; Elizabeth; Richard; Andy; Barry(1982).
    Charles Given's home (El Paso).
  - Gluck, Alex. (Box 6)
    Alex Gluck's kosher butcher shop (El Paso; 1988).
    Alex Gluck at work (1984).
    Doris Gluck at work (wife of Alex Gluck?; 1988).
    Interior Gluck's kosher butcher shop.
    NEGATIVES sheets.
    Two contact sheets of Alex Gluck and his kosher butcher shop.
  - Goldman, Jim: Jim Goldman (1980s). (Box 6)
  - Goldman, Nathan: Two men (Nathan Goldman on the right). (Box 6)
  - Goodman family. (Box 6)
    Joseph Hillel Goodman (El Paso).
    Mrs. Joe H. Goodman.
    Joseph Hillel Goodman's home.
    Aaron Goodman.
    Levy Goodman's home.
  - Guttman, Mosae: Mosae Guttman and son Joseph H. Guttman(El Paso; 1924). (Box 6)
  - Heineman, Otto: Group photo: Hilda; August; Otto Heineman(El Paso; 1922). (Box 6)
  - Horwitz family: Invitation to the birthday party of Florence and Albert Horwitz (El Paso). (Box 6)
  - Kahn, Simon: Article: Simon Kahn and his bakery business (started in 1912; El Paso); NEGATIVES. (Box 6)
  - Kapilowitz-Brown Dairy (El Paso, TX). (Box 6)
    Bob Brown at work feeding cows; he is husband of Blanche Kapilowitz.
    Aerial view of the Kapilowitz-Brown Dairy.
  - Kleinfeld, Saul. (Box 6)
    Saul Kleinfeld with the Harlem Globetrotters Basketball team in El Paso.
    Group photograph of Saul Kleinfeld and Mark Goldberg (both seated) with two El Paso - Juarez (Mexico) children and a woman who benefited from their community efforts.
    Saul Kleinfeld awarding baseball player Micky Rivers something to honor him (1961).
    Group photo: Kleinfeld and two unidentified men shaking hands (1967).
    Portrait of Saul Kleinfeld as a referee standing outside of a boxing ring.
    Group photo commemorating an athletic event (1960): Julian Bershew; Marvin Roth; Saul Kleinfeld; Bobby Goldfarb; Milton Cherno; Maury Cohen.
  - Kohlberg, Ernest. (Box 6)
    Interior of the Kohlberg Brothers Cigar Store (1890); three central figures (l-r): Siegfried Aronstein (bookkeeper); Ernest Kohlberg (proprietor); Saul Isaacs (clerk).
    Exterior photograph of the Kohlberg Bros. La Internacional Factory and Store; standing in front of store: Siegried Aronstein; Chato(wooden Indian); Adolph Solomon (mayor of El Paso).
    Ernest Kohlberg (1904).
    Olga Bernstein Kohlberg at age 41 (1905).
    Walter Lionel Kohlberg (1914).
    Genevieve McHugh Kohlberg (1914).
    Herbert Kohlberg.
    Group photo; front row (l-r): Herbert; Leo Kohlberg; Ernest Kohlberg; Elsa Betty; Olga Kohlberg; Ernest brother's wife; Walter; Ernest's brother.
  - Krakauer family. (Box 6)
    Adolph Krakauer (?).
    Two unidentified adults and two unidentified children in an automobile.
    Dinner menu for a 25th anniversary (1898); either for Luis's parents or Max Krakauer; in Chihuahua.
    Exterior view of house in Chihuahua; with Max Krakauer, Luis's grandfather, Georgie and unidentified child.
  - Krupp, Haymon. (Box 6)
    Portrait of Haymon Krupp (ca. 1910).
    "Official Map of El Paso, Texas" (April 1923).
    Exterior photo of Haymon and Becky Krupp's home.
    Haymon Krupp.
    Bernard Krupp in an El Paso downpour (March 1981).
    View of an oil well; caption reads "Santa Rita No. 1....first oil well discovery on University of Texas lands.... dedicated as a permanent memorial... memorial will stand at the 19th Street-San Jacinto Boulevard entrance to the campus.... be honored w ill be the late Haymon Krupp of El Paso, developer of the Big Lake Field in Reagan County."
    Exterior view of city hall in El Paso (1898); caption contains historical notes: "...used by Haymon Krupp...now owned by Oskar Rosen and his firm, The Limited Inc."
    Three unidentified individuals standing in front of palm trees (ca. 1928).
    Family portrait (ca. 1910).
  - Ku Klux Klan. (Box 6)
    "Frontier Klansman" (El Paso; Dec. 29, 1922).
    Article entitled "Frontier Klan and the Jew" (1922).
  - Levy, Leslie. (Box 6)
    Leslie Levy of El Paso at San Pedro, CA in army training (1918).
    Postal card photo of Leslie Levy and Louis Aronson near the war front (1918).
  - Lowenberg, Carl: Carl Lowenberg (El Paso). (Box 6)
  - Mathias home (El Paso, TX): Albert Mathias's home. (Box 6)
  - Nordwald family. (Box 6)
    Building with sign which reads "H.Nordwald - Mayor y Menor" (1888).
    Ben and Augstia; Otto Nordwald (El Paso; ca.1898).
    Ben and Otto Nordwald (ca.1912).
    Group portrait (Chihuahua; Sept. 25, 1917).
    Rose Norwald.
    Man holding hat.
    Rose Nordwald and baby Ruth.
    Baby photograph of Otto Norwald (?).
    Unidentified individuals sitting around a dining room table.
    Unidentified musical group.
    Document granting Benjamin Norwald permission to carry firearms in Mexico (1918).
    Citizenship papers for Heineman Norwald (April 6, 1878).
  - Rosenfield family. (Box 6)
    Leon Rosenfield (El Paso).
    Estelle Lyon Rosenfield.
  - Scherr, Jim. (Box 7)
    Jim Scherr (El Paso; July 28, 1977).
    Jim Scherr (November 5, 1979).
    Jim Scherr (September 30, 1980).
    Jim Scherr (November 16, 1982).
  - Schuster store (El Paso, TX): Exterior view of the B. Schuster & Co. (El Paso; ca.1883). (Box 7)
  - Schutz store (El Paso, TX). (Box 7)
    Original store of Samuel Schutz and his brother (Franklin [now El Paso]; ca. 1865).
    Samuel Schutz building.
  - Schwartz family. (Box 7)
    NEGATIVES and contact sheets showing "The Popular" store.
    NEGATIVES and contact sheet showing Schwartz business documents.
    Group of men looking for the new plans for the Banett Store: Edward F. Schwartz; Herbert M. Schwartz; Albert J. Schwartz. On the wall in the photographs (l-r): Adolf Schwartz; Maurice Schwartz; Ignatz Weiss (ca. 1959).
    "The Popular" - on the corner of El Paso and Overland Streets (1902).
    Guarantee of deed ownership (1903-1906); NEGATIVE.
    Immigration papers from the American Consulate in Budapest, Hungry.
    Schwartz Dry Goods Store European account (May 31, 1940).
    Interior of a clothing store.
    Mr. and Mrs. Maurice Schwartz at a concert (December 1944).
    Exterior of "The Popular" store.
    Interior of "The Popular."
    Ignatz Weiss and his sister Rose (early 1900s).
    View of Popular service building.
    Map of Hungary; circled is Miskolc.
    Street map of the location of "The Popular."
    Document in German which mentions the name L. Maurice; NEGATIVE.
    Charter of the A. Schwartz Company.
    "Popular Department Store" in El Paso.
    "Popular Department Store's" sign noting closure for Jewish High Holidays (1980).
    Plaques in "The Popular: honoring Adolf Schwartz, Maurice Schwartz, Manuel Schwartz, Erwin Schwartz (1988); contact sheets and NEGATIVES.
    Anne Schwartz Goodman in front of her home; contact sheets and NEGATIVES.
    Adolf Schwartz.
    Ervin Howard Schwartz.
    Maurice Schwartz.
    Schwartzes' home and the Luis Zork family’s home.
    Schwartzes' home on Rim Road.
    Maurice Schwartz's home.
    Interior of Schwartz family business (ca. 1890s).
    Contact and NEGATIVE sheets: home of A. Schwartz and Luis Zork.
    Contact and NEGATIVE sheets showing Ann Schwartz Goodman.
  - Schwartz, Irving. (Box 7)
    Drawing: Chinese man who lived in South El Paso.
    Drawing: Captain Huges of the Texas Rangers.
    Drawing: table Arrangement in the Shwartzes' first home.
    Drawing: weighing in before a cock fight.
    Drawing: border patrolman and friend.
  - Solomon, Adolph. (Box 7)
    Kohlberg Bros. store; shows Adolph Solomon (mayor of El Paso).
    Adolph Solomon (first president of Temple Mount Sinai; 1899).
  - Stolaroff family: Family portrait (back row, l-r): Aaron Stolaroff; Annie Halpern; Ben Dubiniski; Mary Hyman Stolaroff; (middle row): Rose Potash; Sarah Schwartzhard (?); Fannie Schwartzhard Dubiniski; (seated): Solomon Stolaroff (ca.1900). (Box 7)
  - Temple Mt. Sinai (El Paso, TX). (Box 7)
    Cement block that states "New Temple Mt. Sinai 5676/1916."
    Temple Mt. Sinai (1944).
    Temple Mt. Sinai parsonage of Martin Zielonka's family, Wendell Philips's family, and Floyd S. Fierman's family.
    Temple Mt. Sinai.
    Eternal light of Mt. Sinai.
    Torah scrolls of Temple Mt. Sinai (1987).
    Ark containing Torah scrolls.
    "Bird's eye view Mt. Franklin in background, El Paso, Texas 1900."
    Mt. Sinai basketball team (ca. 1917).
    Proclamation from October 13, 1919.
    Dedication services (December 8-10, 1916).
    Medieval wedding ring.
    Documentation from Temple Mt. Sinai (1988).
    Plaque commemorating the structure where the first Jewish synagogue in El Paso was erected.
    Contact and NEGATIVE sheets showing medieval wedding ring; Torah scrolls; endowed chairs of the Schwartz family; monument; exterior of temple; interior of temple.
  - United States military camps in Texas during the Mexican Revolution. (Box 7)
    Camp Cotton (National Guard Section); Michigan Regiment?(summer 1916).
    Camp Stewart's field kitchen and ovens (Fall, 1916).
    Camp Owen Bierne (South Carolina National Guard; ca. 1916).
    Camp Newton D. Baker; tents and buildings (ca. 1916-1919).
    Camp Pershing (ca. 1916 - 1919).
    Generals Alvaro Obregon, Francisco Villa (?) and John J. Pershing meeting on the international bridge after the overthrow of Huerta.
    24th infantry (made up of African Americans) prior to marching into Juarez (1919).
  - Zork family. (Box 7)
    Isadore Zork (El Paso).
    Gus Zork.
    Louis Zork.
    Bertha Zork (ca. July 1888).
    Group photo (l-r): Eddie Steffin; Luis Zork at about 14 years old; Gus Zork; Sydney Frankel at about 14 years old.
    Gustave and Bertha Zork's home.
- Series IV: California.
  - Beth Jacob Congregation (San Diego). (Box 7)
    Postcard showing the sanctuary of Beth Jacob Congregation.
    Various buildings that Beth Jacob Congregation has occupied.
  - Cohn, Louis: Photograph of Louis Cohn, who owned a clothing store in San Bernadino, California. (Box 7)
  - Ott, Rabbi Jacob: Rabbi Jacob Ott - head of Sephardic Temple Tifereth Israel (Los Angeles). (Box 7)
  - Rochlin, Fred: Fred Rochlin. (Box 7)
  - Rochlin, Harriet: Harriet Rochlin giving a speech at the University of Arizona. (Box 7)
  - Solomon, Dutch: Photo of Dutch Solomon at his 80th birthday (La Mesa). (Box 7)
  - Sonora Hebrew Cemetery. (Box 7)
    Memorial at the Sonora Hebrew Cemetery; memorial says "Established in approximately 1851 by the Hebrew Congregation of Sonora..."
    Headstone for Caroline infant (daughter of Henry and Hanah Oppenheimer).
    Headstones in the Sonora Hebrew Cemetery.
  - Temple Adat Shalom (Poway, CA). (Box 7)
    Exterior of Temple Adat Shalom.
    Cantor Lori Wilensky Frank and Rabbi Deborah Ering(?).
  - Temple Beth Emet (Anaheim): Postcard showing the Holy Ark - dedicated on June 2, 1963. (Box 7)
  - Temple Beth Israel (San Diego): Temple Beth Israel. (Box 7)
  - Temple Beth Shalom (Chula Vista). (Box 7)
    Exterior of Temple Beth Shalom (1992).
    Hanukkah Menorah (December 4, 1994).
  - Temple Solel (Encenitas, CA). (Box 7)
    Exterior of Temple Solel.
    Bimah (stage) in sanctuary; ark holding the Torahs; the Eternal Light; Shabbat candles.
    Bimah; ark; four Torah scrolls (1995).
    Sanctuary; benches and shelves; prayer books (1995).
    Hallway and the doors that lead to the sanctuary (1995).
    Gift shop (1995).
    Wall hanging depicting an older man blowing a shofar (1995).
    Wall hanging showing a city and a sun and a quote in English and in Hebrew (1995).
    Wall hanging showing a Star of David within a circle(1995).
  - Weinberger, Jacob: The Jacob Weinberger United States Court House in San Diego. (Box 7)
  - Welisch family. (Box 7)
    Herman Welisch (brother of Theodore and husband of Louise[Horn]).
    Home of Theodore Welisch and Julia Zeckendorf (Tucson).
    Walter Welisch (?) driving (1911; Golden Gate Park, San Francisco).
    Group at picnic in Guernewood Park (about 75 miles north of San Francisco). Includes (l-r): Theodore Welisch; Minnie Rothschild; Sigmund Rothschild; Pauline Rothschild; Walter T. Welisch; Ida (Rothschild) Welisch; Marjorie Welisch.
    Letter to A. Chanin from M. Taylor (1991); explains photos and genealogies of family.
  - Young Leadership: Young Leadership meeting (San Diego - Hotel Del Coronado); Marvin Volk and Benjamin Brook present. (Box 7)
- Series V: Miscellaneous
  - Congregation Aaron (Trinidad, Colorado). (Box 7)
    Centennial Commemoration (1883-1983); Hyman and Bertha Danoff.
    Congregation Aaron.
  - Art (Jewish). (Box 7)
    "Evening and Morning Service for the New Year" (for Spanish and Portuguese Jews).
    "Book of Genesis."
    Assorted religious art work.
  - Auckland Hebrew Congregation and Community Centre (New Zealand): Postcard of Centre located on Greys Avenue, Auckland, New Zealand, founded 1967. (Box 7)
  - Australia: NEGATIVES. (Box 7)
  - Brown, Litman: Litman Brown and Ruth Burnstein Brown(1906). (Box 7)
  - Chihuahua church (Mexico). (Box 7)
  - Copenhagen church (Denmark): Interior view; a plaque with the tetragrammaton in Hebrew. (Box 7)
  - Dow, Rabbi Y.: Rabbi and Mrs. Y. Dow and their children Meyer, Aaron, and Esther. (Box 7)
  - Elias, Joseph. (Box 7)
  - Elkin, Judith (Ann Arbor, MI): Judith Elkin (president of the Latin American Jewish Studies Association). (Box 7)
  - Inquisition. (Box 7)
  - Israel (Abe Chanin's 1976 trip). (Box 7)
    Gush Emunim - West Bank settlement Beth El.
    Arab women in a West Bank village; ceremonial procession.
    Allenby Bridge over Jordan River; Israeli soldiers on left, Jordanian soldiers directing traffic.
    Two soldiers.
    Sunset.
    Elderly Arab man standing in front of a wall with Arabic words written on it.
    Elderly woman in a marketplace in Israel.
    Two young children playing together.
    Elderly man covering an object with a black cloth.
    Barbed wire fence; group of people standing in the background.
    Elderly bearded man in the Old City of Jerusalem.
    Alley in the Old City of Jerusalem.
    Man lying down in a marketplace next to a pile of purple eggplants.
    Four children standing in a doorway.
    Abe and Mildred Chanin sitting with an unidentified man.
    Panoramic view of the Negev Desert.
    Panoramic view of the Golan Heights.
    Five contact sheets.
  - Israel (Abe Chanin's 1980 trip). (Box 7)
    Group of unidentified men; Abe Chanin.
    View of a Kibbutz in the Golan Heights.
    View of road on the border of Israel and Syria.
    Entrance of a bunker in Israel.
    View of a cemetery with headstones stacked on their sides.
    View of the Golan Heights.
    A gunnery in front of the Mediterranean Sea.
    Grave of Avi Mezrah.
    View of a United Nations Building.
  - Israel (Yale Shapiro's 1963 trip). (Box 7)
    Monument at Mt. Hertzel.
    Torah mantles.
    View of Haifa.
    View of Massada.
    Yale Shapiro at Massada.
  - Kotosky family. (Box 7)
    Simon Kotosky (ca. 1930).
    Dora Kotosky with her grandson Tad Thai (1931).
  - Map of the United States: Map page taken from "The Prairie Traveler." (Box 7)
  - Potash, Harold. (Box 7)
  - Rosen, Hymer. (Box 7)
  - Rosen, Steven. (Box 7)
  - Spanish expulsion of the Jews (1492): SLIDES. (Box 7)
  - Vitoria (Spain) Jewish cemetery: Headstone in the Jewish cemetery in Vitoria, Spain. (Box 7)
  - Unidentified photographs. (Box 7)